Hello everyone, I am Ajith from Dito
Insurance. In this video, we
will talk about the most popular policies provided by Tata AG Health Insurance.
Medicare Medicare Lite Medicare
Premier Medicare Plus Super Topup
and Even Elder Care The Tata brand
needs no special introduction.
Tata is the one with the trust factor.
But our goal is to provide you with actual help by considering all the coverage
details, conditions, and hidden
limitations before taking out insurance
.  So watch the video completely,
otherwise there is a chance that you will only look at the premiums and
buy the wrong policy.  But if
you still have doubts or want to start your insurance
journey, book a free call with our team
.  Link
is in the description. Zero cost.
Our health insurance
experts will provide clear explanations. First, a
short intro about the company. Tata AIG started in 2001
.  This is a joint venture between the Tata Group and the American AG
Group.  There are
249 officers, 100,000 plus
agents and 11,000 plus network
hospitals across Pan India.  Overall, the
insurer has a strong establishment and the average
claim settlement ratio
is 96%.  This means that out of every 100 claims,
96 claims are approved.   The
complaint rate is also low, with just
11 complaints
registered for every 10,000 claims.  And the company's
performance is good.  Now let's
move on to policies.  First of all, Tata
AI Medicare, so this plan has
decent coverage for most everyone.
Even the premium is not too expensive.
Sum insured options available in this policy range from 3 locks
to 20 locks
.  People between the ages of 18 and 65
can consider this policy.  If you have dependent kids, you
can also include them in the plan for a period of three months to 25 years.  There is
no limit on room selection in this policy.
We can select any room we want
.  Sweet room, deluxe room, any
category, it's up to you.  There are
also no restrictions like penalty payments
.  This means that the entire hospital expenses will be
covered by the insurance company
.  We don't have to bear 10% to 20% of expenses
and there are no sub-limits depending on the disease
.  That means there are
25,000 pills for Cataracts, 40,000 for various
disease-related supplements, and so on
.
We can claim up to sum and short for any medical condition
.  And you may incur many medical expenses, such as
tests,
diagnostics, doctor visits, and
tablets, starting 60 days before your admission date.
So all of that
will be covered too.  And
this coverage will be extended for up to 90 days even after discharge
.  We call this pre-
and post-hospital coverage.  And
even if you make a claim, the coverage will be
restored and given to you.  But it is
restored only once a year
.  Even if it is the same disease, it
will be restored, but if it is the same
disease, we will have to wait 45 days
.  We provide coverage for day care
treatments like cataract surgery,
dialysis, and all of these things up to the full sum
insured
.  And domiciliary treatment
coverage is also available.  If you
need to receive treatment at home, that
will also be covered.  And full coverage is also being provided for Ayush treatments,
i.e. treatments like Ayurveda and Homeopathy
.  And
after every claim-free year, we are given a 50% sum
insured bonus.  So this will be
provided up to a maximum of 100%.   This
means that after I take 10 locks, the
next two years are claim free years,
but if I do not make any claims, I will have a
coverage of 10 locks base cover plus
10 locks bonus.  The health
check benefit will be activated after two claim-free years
.
Coverage is provided up to a maximum of 10,000.   There will
also be inbuilt consumables coverage
.  This means that expenses like gloves, syringes, and PPE
kits will also be
covered by the insurance company.
And if there is no vaccination coverage like typhoid,
then we are being provided immediate cover for vaccines like anti-rabies
.  But
for HPV and Hepatitis P vaccines, there must be two
years of continuous coverage.
In case of accidental death, the entire base sum
insured will be paid to the nominee.  This is an
optional benefit.  And the limitations are that the
bonus amount will decrease after the year it is claimed
.  And the restoration benefit is
only available once a year.  Similarly, there will
be global cover, but you must
prove that the diagnosis was made in India.
Again, if you need to compare policies and
know the features clearly,
book a free call with our Dito team.  This saves time and
also helps you make the right decision.
The link is in the description.  Now
let's see. When you hear the name Medicare Lite, you
know that it is a light version that can
be taken on a budget, but the coverage is also limited
.  Sum insured is available for us from 5 lakhs
to 20 lakhs
.  And the same eligibility can be taken from 18 years
to 65 years of age
.  But there is a room rent limit
.  Only single private rooms are allowed
.  Nothing fancy.  If we
take a plan after the age of 61, a 20% co-
payment is also added to us as a compulsory payment.
Also, if you receive treatment
anywhere other than at Tata AG Preferred Network hospitals, a
30% co-
payment will apply again.  This means that if you
get a bill of 100,000, you will have to pay 30,000 and the
insurance company will pay 70,000.  We provide coverage for pre-
hospitalization expenses for up
to 60 days and post-
hospitalization expenses for up to 180 days
.
Restoration is only available once a year for the
same illness and there is a 45-day cooling
period, so if you want to use it
again for treatment for the same medical condition,
you will have to wait 45 days to use the restoration amount
.  Vaccination coverage is being
provided to us up to 5000
.  There is
no waiting period for anti-rabies and typhoid vaccines.
We also have a waiting period of years for HPV and Hepatitis B.
In addition, Hearing Eight is also covered
.  Up to 50% of actual cost, subject to a maximum of Rs.
10,000. This is activated only after every three years of
continuous coverage
.  And the no claim
bonus is also 50% up to 100% on annual
health checkups, but
only the listed tests
are cashless.  And overall, if you see a low premium
but high limitations, then in case you
want the best plan within your budget but need to
clearly understand the policy details,
book a call with our team
.  If you have better options, please suggest them
.  Book the Free Call Link
is in the Description Next Tata
AIG Medicare Premier This plan is
the most feature-rich plan in Tata AIG but
it also has an equal cost.  The sum
insured can be taken from 5 lakhs to 3 crores
.  There is no entry age same room rent
limit, no co-payment, and
obviously no disease-wise sub-limits either
.
Expenses are also covered 60 days prior to hospital admission.
And coverage is provided for up to 90 days after discharge
.  If
you take a cover amount of 50 lakhs or less,
this coverage
will be extended to 200 days if you take a cover amount of 75 lakhs or more.
And the restore benefit will also
be the same.  If we get the same illness only once this year,
we will have to
serve a cooling period of up to 45 days.
Health check-ups are given every year.
Coverage, whether claimed or not, ranges
from 10,000 to 25,000 depending on the cover
amount. This amount varies.  And
there is also global coverage, but once diagnosed in India, you have to
go abroad only for treatment.
Vaccination coverage is also very detailed
.  And depending on the insured, there is
also additional cover for newborn babies
.  And maternity coverage
was also provided.  If it is a girl child, there will
be an additional coverage of Rs. 10,000.  And
complication cover of up to 25,000 was given.
Newborn vaccination cover varies from
10,000 to 15,000 based on the cover amount for one year post birth
.  And OPD consultations will
start being provided after two years of pharmacy cover.  The amount depends
on the sum insured. Dental OPD
treatments are also covered after two years
.  So we also cover treatments like root canal
filling and extraction
.  The downside is that
all features
are limited to a limited amount.  Competitors
like Aditya Birla R Care offer high
restoration benefits and a better bonus
structure.  If you still
believe in the Tata brand and
want a flagship plan, this is the best option.
Next is Tata AIG Elder Care, which is
for senior citizens with an
entry age of 65 years to 85 years.  So, some
insured options are available to us, ranging from 5 locks
to 25 locks
.  And
only single private rooms are provided in room selection
there is no domiciliary treatment coverage, meaning that if you have to receive treatment from home, the
insurance company
will not provide that coverage.  And pre- and post-
hospitalization coverage is provided for only 30 days and
60 days.
And there is no benefit like restoration.
On top of that, we have a mandatory 20%
severance payment.  This means that
after taking out the policy, you will have to pay 20% of the expenses for each claim, while the
insurance company will pay 80%.
We also have sub-limits for medical conditions such as cataracts and joint surgeries
.  This means you cannot use the full cover amount
.  This will change based on our location
and the amount of money we have saved
.  And health checkups are
provided only after every two claim-free years.  But if
you pay an extra premium, the co-payment will be
waived.  This means that we don't need to pay a co-payment of 20%
.  Otherwise,
you will have to pay an extra premium for it
.  So, this policy
provides us with very basic coverage
.  And
you should only consider this policy if there are no other options
.  And the final plan is Medicare
Plus Super Top.  This is a super top up
plan.  So we have the chance to set a deductible from 2 lakhs
to 20 lakhs in this
.  And we have some insured options ranging
from 3 lakhs to 1 crore
.  This acts as an add-on to the base policy
.  So in this policy, we have
no room rent restrictions and
no co-payments.  On top of that, we are
also providing domiciliary coverage, day care coverage, and AYUSH benefits
.  Otherwise, there is
no restoration benefit.  And an annual
health checkup is
provided to us free of charge after every two claim-free years
.  If you want global coverage,
it is provided as an optional benefit
.  If
you already have a corporate
policy or an existing base policy,
this super top-up could be the perfect choice for you by taking higher premiums
.  Now if we look at the premium,
again the premiums vary depending on one's age and the
variant they are taking
.  On my screen you can see a few
examples,
so price wise it's okay, but value wise you have to
carefully analyze which plan suits you.
Finally, if you have faith in the Tata brand and
want decent coverage, you
can consider these plans.
But if you want better bonuses, fast pre-
existing disease coverage,
or even more innovative features, there
are better options in the market.  But before making a decision,
book a free call with the Dito team to
give you policy comparisons and explanations. Our job link is in the description
.  I'm Ajith, I hope this detailed
video helped you
.  If you have any more questions, please
comment.  See you again in the next video
with a different product review,
Until Then Take Care Boy.